Contact Info



+91 8939266125



Chennai



sharathdfire@gmail.com



LinkedIn: linkedin.com/in/sharath-chandran-dillibabu-50ab92153

SKILLS

Manual Testing

- Good knowledge with SDLC.
- Exposure in Black box testing.
- Good knowledge in STLC.
- ➤ Good knowledge in Defect life cycle.
- Good exposure in Test plan.
- Levels of Testing.
- Agile Methodology.

Automation Testing

- Core Java (Basic Knowledge)
- Selenium Web-driver.
- TestNG Framework.
- Cucumber BDD Framework.
- Git, Jenkins and Maven.
- Management tools- JIRA, RedMine.

Internship & Certifications

- Manual and Automation Training, Feb 2018 to May 2018.
- Design Intern in PECPL, Oct 2017 to Jan 2018.
- Pipeline Design Training, Feb 2017 to June 2017.

SHARATH CHANDRAN D

SOFTWARE TEST ENGINEER

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am a Quality Analyst with holistic knowledge of software testing. I have 3+ years of experience in all levels of testing, including functional, integration, system, and user acceptance. Worked on multiple projects involving both web & mobile based applications.

WORK EXPERIENCE

July 2021 – Present

Indium Software (India) Private Ltd.

Software Testing Engineer

- Analyzing the Scope documents and Identifying the Test Scenarios.
- Building up the Test Cases and Involved in peer review of Test Cases.
- Executing the Test cases and tracking the defect in defect tracking tool.
- Preparing the Test summary reports.

May 2018 - June 2021

SolvEdge Technology (India) Private Ltd.

Software Testing Engineer (Trainee)

- Analyzing the user requirements and Identifying the Test Scenarios.
- Building up the Test Cases and Involved in peer review of Test Cases.
- Executing various testing phases and tracking the defect in defect tracking tool.
- Locating the web elements in Selenium WebDriver using Xpath.
- Preparing and executing of the Java scripts using Selenium-TestNG framework.
- Code development and execution of the scripts using Selenium- Cucumber BDD framework.

PROJECTS

CHS Cigna PDP (Health care)

Project Description

Enrolling a member in a web based application which provides the members Medicare details (Prescription Drug Plan) for the CHS.

Testing Knowledge / Application Tested

- Automation and Manual testing.
- Web Based Applications.
- Mobile Applications.

Educational History

- Bachelor of Engineering 72.4%
 (08/2012-04/2016)
 Prince Dr. K. Vasudevan College of Engineering and Technology
- HSC- 75.5%
 (07/2011- 04/2012)

 Prince Matriculation Higher Sec.
 School, Chennai.
- SSLC-84.4%
 (07/2009-04/2010)

 Prince Matriculation Higher Sec.
 School, Chennai.

My Indium App / TRIMMS

Project Description

A Web and Mobile based application designed for employee to maintain the timesheet. Also it provides the updated news of HR and Marketing Announcements for the employees.

Recovery Coach (Health care)

Project Description

A Web and Mobile based application designed to guide the patients during their entire surgical journey. Also it prompts notification alerts to patients and physicians in case of emergency.

Hospital Reported Outcomes (HRO)

Project Description

A Web based application clearly explains about the hospital performance and helps in to improve the quality of the hospitals.

EchoLog (Mobile App)

Project Description

EchoLog is made to improve on paper logbook and makes better way to log your ultrasound scan reports digitally.